Guide to the William Upcott, Collection of Autograph Letters
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
[Collection of autograph letters of various English literati]
1701-1800
OSBORN C231
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
0.06
(1 volume)
MSS.
Upcott, William, 1779-1845
Immediate Source of Acquisition
For provenance information, consult the appropriate curator.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
The following finding aid is a complete inventory of the contents of Osborn c231. This list was reformatted from previously existing cataloging.
Antiquarians -- Great Britain -- Correspondence; Great Britain -- Intellectual life -- 18th century; Great Britain -- Social life and customs -- 18th century; Correspondence; Ducarel, Andrew Coltee, 1713-1785; Hawkins, John Sidney, 1758-1842; Le Neve, Peter, 1661-1729; Massey, W. (William), 1691-1764?; Maurice, Thomas, 1754-1824; Morant, Philip, 1700-1770; Nichols, John, 1745-1826; Price, Richard, 1723-1791; Shaw, Stebbing, 1762-1802; Somers, John Somers, Baron, 1651-1716; Tonson, Jacob, 1656?-1736; Upcott, William, 1779-1845; Vallancey, Charles, 1721-1812; Wilkins, William, 1778-1839; Royal Society (Great Britain)
- Osborn c231
  - [BIOGRAPHICAL NOTES ON JOHN NICHOLS (1745-1826)]:
    - Anonymous MS, n.d. (Box 1)
      Scope and Contents
      n.p.
      4 p.; 22 x 14 cm.
      With wrapper sheet, addressed in
      another hand to William Upcott,
      (1779-1845).
      231/13
  - HAWKINS, JOHN SIDNEY, 1758-1842
    - ALS to William Wilkins (1778-1830) (Box 1)
      Twickenham
      3 p.; 23 x 19 cm.
      Architecture of the House of
      Commons.
      231/1
  - LE NEVE, PETER, 1661-1729
    - Letter [copy] to John Somers, 1st baron Somers (1661-1729), 1699 Dec 22 (Box 1)
      3 p.; 22 x 18 cm.
      231/12
  - MASSEY, WILLIAM, 1691-1764
    - ALS to Andrew Coltee Ducarel, (1713-1785) (Box 1)
      1754 Jun 24, Wandsworth
      4 p.; 21 x 16 cm.
      231/4
  - MORANT, PHILIP, 1700-1770
    - ALS to [Andrew Coltee Ducarel (1713-1785)], 1754 Jul 25 (Box 1)
      4 p.; 23 x 19 cm.
      Alien Priories.
      231/3
  - PRICE, RICHARD, 1723-1791
    - [Memorandum on Assurance] (Box 1)
      5 p.; 23 x 19 cm.
      Written for Dr. John Calder
      (1733-1815), it is endorsed with
      initials by William Upcott
      231/11
  - SHAW, STEBBING, 1762-1802
    - ALS to Richard Gough (1735-1809), 1735 Aug 9 (Box 1)
      Statfold
      Compiling Gough's pedigree.
      231/2
  - TONSON, JACOB, 1656-1736
    - ALS to an unnamed recipient, 1719 (Box 1)
      Paris
      3 p.; 24 x 18 cm.
      Speaks about books for John Law
      (1671-1729).
      231/10
  - VALLANCEY, CHARLES, 1721-1812
    - ALS to Thomas Maurice (1754-1824), 1806 Jul 23 (Box 1)
      Dublin
      1 p.; 24 x 19 cm.
      Irish Origins.
      231/5
  - VALLANCEY, CHARLES, 1721-1812
    - ALS to Thomas Maurice (1754-1824), 1805 Dec 10 (Box 1)
      7 p.; 24 x 19 cm.
      231/6
  - VALLANCEY, CHARLES, 1721-1812
    - ALS to Thomas Maurice (1754-1824), 1805 Aug 4 (Box 1)
      3 p.; 24 x 19 cm.
      Etymologies.
      231/7